<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Africa Arusha 2022</title>
    <description>DSA Arusha 2022</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/dsa2022arusha/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/dsa2022arusha/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Summer School</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the tradition of previous Data Science Africa events, a summer school on machine learning and data science will be held prior to the main workshop. This summer school will target graduate students, researchers, and professionals working with huge amounts of data or unique datasets. The DSA 2022 Arusha Summer School will be hosted by the Institute of Accountancy Arusha (&lt;b&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://iaa.ac.tz/&quot;&gt;IAA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;) in Tanzania. Summer School starts on the 18th to 20th of July 2022. The summer school will also involve end-to-end tutorial sessions from professionals walking the participants through introductory and advanced lectures in data science and machine learning as well as moderate to advanced practical and tutorial sessions where participants will get their hands wet wrangling and munging datasets and applying cutting edge machine learning techniques to derive inference from the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this end, we require that participants are well versed in the basics of the technologies and languages that will be used in the summer school. Particularly we want to make sure participants have sufficient base skills in Python programming, Data Science, and Machine learning. You are required to &lt;b&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://bit.ly/39mqlpt&quot;&gt;DOWNLOAD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; the corresponding notebook complete the notebook and then fill out the registration form below that requires you to upload the ZIP file of the completed notebook. 
Register by submitting your Notebooks &lt;b&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://forms.gle/6Jbn3EDDWtAutY3Q9&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--For more info, contact us at [dsakampala2020@gmail.com](mailto:dsakampala2020@gmail.com)--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 03:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dsa2022arusha/blog/summer-school</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/dsa2022arusha/blog/summer-school</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Workshop</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This year’s DSA event will be physical, starting on the 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; of July, 2022 hosted by the Institute of Accountancy Arusha located in Arusha City, Tanzania. We believe that the DSA community of both past and new participants can still benefit greatly from the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DSA Arusha event will consist of oral presentations of data science applications from academia and industry and interactive panel discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theme for the summer school is Data, Technology and Community. We want to improve the community engagement in Data Science in Africa, by empowering communities and researchers to consider their role in responsible AI practices in Africa. We strongly encourage the participation of data science communities from across the continent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also using this platform as a call for abstracts for the workshop. Abstracts should cover relevant topics including but not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Science for the Sustainable Development Goals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Health care&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agriculture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wildlife conservation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Disaster response&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Geo-spatial modeling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Telecommunications data modeling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Economic monitoring&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New data science and machine learning methods&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;COVID related applications&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Language modeling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workshop is scheduled for 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; – 22&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; July 2022 &lt;b&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://bit.ly/3vcFrVz&quot;&gt;registration is open&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional info will be added here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any questions?
Email organizers at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@datascienceafrica.org&quot;&gt;info@datascienceafrica.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 03:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dsa2022arusha/blog/Workshop</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/dsa2022arusha/blog/Workshop</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
